(銀時)というわけで…
今日が 最後の授業です｡
And so, graduation day is finally here. This is the last class.
[Once you graduate, you're an adult! In this episode, we'd like to introduce you to the world children cannot understand.]
[Anime and gambling are very similar. Either it's a big hit, or you lose your shirt.]
Kabukicho... Also known as the Town of Greed.
＜ かぶき町 それは欲望の街｡
この街には
あらゆる快楽が用意されている｡
Many pleasures can be found in this town. Alcohol, women...
酒 女 そして薬｡
And drugs... There's nothing you can't get in this town.
この街で手に入らないものはない｡
And tonight, these men are about to seek challenges on a whole new stage.
そして 今夜 男たちは➡
新たなｽﾃｰｼﾞへと
挑もうとしていた！＞
覚悟は いいか？
Are you ready?
Yeah. Tonight, we'll say goodbye to a life of poverty.
(長谷川)あぁ 今夜で➡
わびしい 貧乏ﾆｰﾄ生活とも
おさらばだ｡
We're gonna win! Until we get kicked out.
勝つぜ 完膚なきまでにな｡
Damn it! I'm gonna win more money than I could ever spend!
(長谷川)おうよ！
使い切れねえほどの あぶく銭➡
この手に つかんでやらぁ！
And we'll celebrate with Dom Perignon mixed with Dom Perignon!
祝杯は ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘの ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ割りだ！
ｹﾞﾘするまで 飲み倒す！
We'll drink until we have the runs!
(２人)ﾚｯﾂ ｶｯｼｰﾉ！
Casino, here we come!
["A Life Without Gambling is like Sushi Without Wasabi"]
(胴元)どちら様も
ようござんすね｡
Is everyone ready?
はぁ！
(胴元)丁か 半か！
Place your bets! Odds or evens! Place your bets!
さぁ はった はった～！
丁！
半！
Evens!
Odds!
半！
(２人)丁～！
Evens!
♪♪～
いやぁ 冬じゃなくて よかったな｡
Boy, I'm glad it isn't winter. We'd be on the verge of freezing to death.
凍えるところだったぜ｡
That's for sure. Although, it's winter in our wallets again.
そうだな 財布のほうは
冬に逆戻りだけどな｡
いやぁ ﾎﾝﾄ ついてるぜ｡
We sure are lucky.
We sure are. The God of Poverty is definitely with us.
そうだな ついてるな｡
貧乏神的なものが
絶対 ついてるなぁ｡
そういや 最近
左肩が重いんだよね｡
Now that I think about it, my left shoulder's been feeling awfully heavy lately.
意味もなく
なんか乗ってる感じなんだよね｡
Like there's someone on it... Like the God of Poverty.
貧乏神的なものが｡
Don't you think it's drooping a bit? My left shoulder?
曲がってない？
左肩 なんか曲がってない？
気にし過ぎなんだよ｡
You worry too much. If you look too desperate, even Lady Luck will avoid you.
陰気なﾂﾗしてたら
ﾂｷも逃げちまうぜ｡
ｵﾚもよ 最近なんか でけえ鎌
持った 不気味なおっさんが➡
Lately I keep seeing this creepy old man carrying a huge sickle.
視界に ちらつくんだけど➡
But I've decided not to worry about him.
もう 気にしないことにしたよ｡
I think you should be worried.
(長谷川)それは
気にしたほうがいいと思う｡
See...? Speaking of the devil...
ほら 言ってるそばから｡
Huh?
ｱﾝﾀの後ろに｡
Behind you.
(長谷川)ぎゃあぁ～！
Akuryotaisan! Youmakoufuku!
[Note: These are all spells to cast off evil. Akuryou taisan = evil scatter/release; is a common charm from Shinto temples. Youma koufuku = phantom scatter.]
悪霊退散！ 妖魔降伏!!
えろいむえっさいむ！
てくまくまやこん!!
Eromuesaimu! Tekumakumayakon!
[Eromuesaimu is a chant from the anime "Akuma-kun." Tekumakumayakon is a chant from the anime "Himitsu no Akko"]
ぬぉっ!?
Look at you clowns. You either have it or you don't.
(勘兵衛)ついてるだ
ついてねえだ➡
And you call yourselves gamblers.
ｱﾝﾀら それでも博打打ちかい？
ｺｲﾂぁ ｵﾚたちが
引っぺがされた着物…｡
Huh? These are...the clothes they won off us!
Who are you?
ｱﾝﾀ いったい…？
Luck's not a snack your grandma gives you.
ばばあの炊き出しじゃねえんだ｡
待ってるだけじゃ
ﾂｷは回ってこねえよ｡
If all you do is wait, Lady Luck won't come.
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙの女神は
ﾃﾒｴで口説き落とさなきゃあよ｡
You have to seduce the goddess of gambling yourself.
(ｷﾞｬﾗﾘｰたち)おぉ～！
He's amazing! He's been raking it in for a while now. Who is he?!
(ｷﾞｬﾗﾘｰ)すっげえよ あの男！
さっきから勝ちまくってるぞ！
何者だ!?
(ｷﾞｬﾗﾘｰ)おい あれ あの顔の傷➡
Hey, that scar on his face. He might be Kanbe, the Luck Reader.
もしかして ﾂｷﾖﾐの勘兵衛…｡
ﾂｷﾖﾐ？
"Luck reader"?
(ｷﾞｬﾗﾘｰ)恐るべき強運をもつ
伝説の博徒｡
The unbeatable gambler with amazing luck.
ﾔﾂは その名のとおり
ﾂｷの流れを読めるって話だ｡
A legend among gamblers! They say he can read how his luck's gonna run.
どんな劣勢も
自分の流れに変えてしまう➡
He can change all odds in his favor... He's every gambler's idol.
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰたちの ｶﾘｽﾏよ｡
I heard he disappeared from Edo for a while.
たしか しばらく
江戸から 姿消してたはずだが➡
まさか この目で拝めるたぁ！
But I never thought I'd get to see him in person!
ﾍｯﾍｯﾍ…｡
(どよめき)
伝説の博徒だかなんだか
知らんが➡
Well, however legendary he is, I didn't know Lady Luck was such a whore.
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙの女神が
こんな尻軽だったとはよ｡
ｵﾚが あんなに必死に口説いても➡
Hell, I've been working my butt off to woo her and she didn't even glance at me.
見向きもしなかったのに｡
妻帯者には 興味ねえんだろ｡
She's probably not interested in married guys.
(長谷川)ﾊﾂなんて
実家に帰ったきり➡
Hatsu went back to her hometown and hasn't come back.
全然 帰ってこねえよ｡
You'd think she could forgive me for a one-night stand.
一夜の過ちくらい
犯してくれてもいいだろ…｡
Maybe the goddess likes the wild type, like him.
あぁいう ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞな感じが
好きなのかね 女神様は｡
(長谷川)あぁそうだ
きっと そうだ｡
Yeah, I'll bet she does. So I'll go wild too!
ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞで いってみよう！
Odds or evens?
(胴元)丁か 半か！
Evens!
(２人)丁～！
Huh? What's wrong? Not wild enough maybe?
なんだぁ 何が悪いんだ｡
ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞさが 足りねえのか？
Can't I get more into the mood of "I don't give a damn"?
なんか もっと
｢ｵﾚなんて どうでもいいんだ｣➡
みたいな感じ 出ねえかな｡
Hasegawa-san, take off your boxers.
長谷川さん ﾊﾟﾝﾂ脱げ｡
えっ｡
Huh? Hey, I don't mind, but I'm not wild, y'know.
(長谷川)おいおい いいけど
あんま ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞじゃねえぞ｡
ｵﾚのは
どっちかっつ～と ﾏｲﾙﾄﾞだよ｡
If anything, mine is more on the mild side.
What're you morons doing?!
(勘兵衛)ｱﾝﾀら 何してんだい！
And after everything I went through to get your clothes back!!
人が せっかく
着物を取り返してやったのに➡
ﾊﾞｶかぁ！
Are you stupid? Go home already! You're not suited to gambling!
もう帰れ お前ら｡
博打 向いてねえんだよ！
(長谷川)ｱﾝﾀが
勝手に やったことだろう！
You did it on your own. I don't remember asking you!
頼んだ覚えはねえ｡
それとも あれか｡
Or what? Could it be the trick to winning Lady Luck is to look shallow but be secretly generous?
ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞさに垣間見える
その優しさが➡
女神をおとす ｺﾂなのかい？
大層なもんだな この野郎｡
You're so full of it. But you better watch your health.
健康に気をつけてよ｡
I'm not forcing myself to be kind!
無理やり 優しさ
垣間見せてんじゃねえよ！
♪♪(ｻｯｸｽ)
(勘兵衛)ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙやってる
ﾔﾂにはなぁ➡
There are two types of gamblers.
２種類の人間がいる｡
The first are guys who simply love to gamble.
１つは単純に 博打が好きなﾔﾂ➡
２つは
博打を打ってる自分が好きなﾔﾂ｡
The second type are guys who think they're cool when they gamble.
The second type makes crazy bets. He gets caught up in his own euphoria and destroys himself.
(勘兵衛)後者が ﾀﾁが悪い｡
ﾑﾁｬな賭けをする自分に陶酔して➡
やがて 持ち崩す｡
The better the gambler, the less extravagant the bets.
腕のいいﾔﾂほど
手堅い博打を打つ｡
危ねえ橋は 勝てると
ふんだとき以外 渡らねえ｡
You don't go for it unless you know you can win.
ｵﾚの見たところ ｱﾝﾀらは２だ｡
You guys are obviously number two. Just take my advice and quit now.
悪いことは言わねえ｡
もう博打は やめるこった｡
２じゃねえよ ３だ｡
We're not number two. We're number three.
ねえよ そんなもん｡
ある｡
There's no such thing.
Sure, there is. The kind who just really needs the money! The easy way.
切実に 金が欲しいﾔﾂだ｡
楽してな｡
働け～！
So get a job!
お前に 労働者の気持がわかるか｡
Like you'd understand a laborer's feelings. Gamblers are frivolous.
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰなんざ
遊び人みてえなもんじゃねえか｡
いや 違うな｡
You're wrong. Life is a gamble. We're all gamblers.
人生なんて
いわば博打みてえなもんだ｡
人は皆 ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰさ｡
うるせえよ｡
Shut up.
とにかく ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰとしては➡
Anyway, a gambler shouldn't hang around in the sacred gambling hall in a pair of boxers.
神聖な賭場で
ﾊﾟﾝﾂ一丁は 気分がよくねえ｡
これ以上 ここを汚すと許さんぞ｡
I won't allow you to sully this place any further.
妙な野郎だな…｡
What a strange guy...
あ あれぇ!?
Huh?
Huh? How did this happened?!
どうして こんなことになった？
何を どこで間違った？
Where'd I go wrong?
おぅおぅ 神聖な賭場を➡
Hey, hey. Is it okay to dirty the sacred gambling hall with your loincloth?
ふんどし一丁で
汚していいのかね？
ぬっ お前ら！
Huh? You guys...!
On top of that, you sullied your name by cheating.
おまけに ｲｶｻﾏで
ﾃﾒｴの名前まで汚しちまって➡
どう思うよ？ 長谷川さん｡
What do you think, Hasegawa-san?
Trying to seduce Lady Luck with magic tricks? How pitiful. Totally pitiful.
手品で
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙの女神を口説くなんざ➡
姑息だよ 姑息｡
And you're supposed to be a legendary gambler!
伝説のｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰが聞いてあきれるな｡
ﾌﾝｯ 言っただろう｡
Humph... I told you. You have to create your own luck!
ﾂｷは自分で つかみ取るものだと｡
おい もうﾀﾞﾝﾃﾞｨｰ路線は ﾑﾘだ｡
Hey, your cool dude act won't work. Not when you're only in a loincloth.
自分の格好を見ろ｡
Well, bad luck sure seems to stick to you two.
しかし お前ら
本当に 悪運が強いらしいな｡
どうやら ｵﾚのﾂｷも
持っていかれちまったようだ｡
It seems you took my good fortune too.
Aw, c'mon. Do us a favor.
だからよぅ １つお願いしますよ｡
ｵﾚたちの悪運を
そのｲｶｻﾏで吹き飛ばして➡
Blast away this bad luck with your little tricks and help us make some money.
ひとっ稼ぎして
いただけないでしょうか？
We won't say a word!
黙っててやるからよ！
Gentlemen...
(黒服)お客様｡
Please come with us.
ちょっと
こちらに来ていただけますか？
やぁ ﾎﾝﾄ ついてるなぁ｡
Man. We never have any luck, do we?
ﾎﾞｸたちって｡
(華蛇)ほぅ… ｺﾔﾂらが➡
So these are the scum who cheated in my gambling den.
ﾜｼの賭場で
ｲｶｻﾏを働こうとした者たちかえ？
(華蛇)たいした度胸じゃのぅ｡
You're pretty gutsy.
この かぶき町四天王が １人➡
There's one ruler in Kabukicho and that's me, Kada the Princess Peacock.
孔雀姫 華蛇を出し抜こうとは…｡
死ぬ覚悟は できておろうのう？
Trying to outwit me? I hope you're prepared to die.
Hold it! Hold it! We didn't chea--!
待て待て！
ｵﾚたちは ｲｶｻﾏなんて… ぶほっ！
I hate men who make excuses! And you call yourself a gambler?
言い訳がましい男は 嫌いじゃ！
おぬし それでも ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰかえ？
Hey, hey. Talk about a goddess.
おいおい… ずいぶんと
おっかねえ女神様だな｡
かぶき町の
ほとんどの賭場を仕切る 女豹よ｡
She's the female boss who controls most of the casinos in Kabukicho.
(勘兵衛)この女の 縄張りで
ﾄﾗﾌﾞったﾔﾂで➡
No one has ever escaped her shackles.
生きて帰ってきたもんは いねえ！
ｵﾚたちも このまま➡
We're doomed to end up at the bottom of the ocean.
海の底だな…｡
ふぅ…｡ んっ？
(華蛇)どこぞで
見た顔じゃと思うたら➡
I wondered where I saw you... You're Kanbe. Kanbe, the "Luck Reader."
おぬしは 勘兵衛｡
ﾂｷﾖﾐの 勘兵衛ではないか｡
ほぅ…
あの江戸で 最強をうたわれた➡
Hmm... So the legendary gambler of Edo turned out to be a mere cheater?
伝説のｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰが
ただの ｲｶｻﾏ師だったとは…｡
(華蛇)そなたの名は ﾜｼの星にまで
轟いておったというのに➡
Your name had reached even my ears.
ﾂｷを読み
どんな劣勢も 覆す男だと…｡
A man who could read and change the course of luck even in the most dire situations.
昔の話さ…｡
That was long ago. Now, my eye has closed, and I can't read anything.
今はもう 目が ふさがっちまって
何も見えねえ｡
I'm just a rotten cheat.
ただの ｲｶｻﾏ師だ｡
Hmm... Your right eye may be closed, but it can still see luck...
ほぅ…
その ふさがった右目ならば➡
ﾂｷが見えると… おもしろい｡
Interesting.
(華蛇)風のｳﾜｻに聞いた｡
Rumors say five years ago, you lost your right eye after losing a big match.
おぬし ５年前に
ある大博打に負け➡
右目を失ったと…｡
But surely, what your right eye can't see, your left eye can.
だが 右目で見えるものが
左目で見えぬわけがあるまい…｡
♪♪～
I shall give you one last chance.
ぬしらに
最後のﾁｬﾝｽをやろう｡
あっ… こりゃあ…！
This is...
どうやら ｵﾚたちの命は
ﾏｰｼﾞｬﾝに委ねられたようだな｡
It seems our last chance will be in mahjong.
おかしくねえ？
お子様ｱﾆﾒﾀｲﾑで ﾏｰｼﾞｬﾝって…｡
Isn't it weird? Mahjong in a time slot featuring children's anime?
ここは 普通 …ﾋｹﾞ 危機一髪とか➡
Shouldn't we be having an exciting challenge with something like Kurohige Kikiippatsu?
[Kurohige Kikiippatsu = Pop-up Pirate. A popular children's game in which you stick plastic swords into a barrel and try to eject Blackbeard the Pirate.]
そんなんで
勝負すんじゃねえのか？
Well, I'm sure there are all kinds of grown-up concerns like sponsors and things.
いや ｽﾎﾟﾝｻｰとか いろいろ➡
大人の事情があるんだろ…｡
(長谷川)ﾏｰｼﾞｬﾝかぁ…➡
Mahjong, eh? I only know the basics.
とりあえず
打ち方くらいは 知ってるが…｡
Huh?!
お… おい… 長谷川さん ｱﾝﾀ…！
H-Hasegawa-san, you...
えっ？ なに？ ｵﾚ どうかした？
Huh? What'd I do? Is there something on...
なんか ついて…
えっ なに これ!? なに これ!?
Huh?! What's this?! What's this? Why only me?! Huh?!
なんで ｵﾚだけ～!? えぇぇ～っ!?
(物音)
(ﾄﾞｱが開く音)
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ｸｯｸｯｸｯｸｯ…｡
(勘兵衛)ｵﾒｴは!?
You're...!
知ってんのか？
(勘兵衛)雀鬼 ｱｶｹﾞ…｡
You know him?
Janki Akage. The pro mahjong player for the Kada Gang.
(勘兵衛)華蛇お抱えの ﾌﾟﾛ雀師だ｡
(勘兵衛)20年間 無敗の男や➡
He's gone twenty years without a single loss.
龍だの虎だのと
呼ばれてる連中を➡
He's wasted guys named Dragon and Tiger one after another.
次々と葬り去り
今や 裏世界じゃ➡
In the underworld,
生きる伝説と
なりつつある男だ…｡
he's a living legend.
Kanbe, the Luck Reader, knows about me? Now that's an honor.
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾂｷﾖﾐの勘兵衛に ｵﾚのことを
知っていてもらえたとは 光栄だ｡
今日は 楽しもうぜ｡
We'll have a lot of fun today.
つまり あれか… ｵﾚたちは➡
In other words, if we beat you, we can leave this place alive?
ｱﾝﾀに勝てば 助かるってことか？
Right... If even just one of you beats me, all three of you can go free.
(ｱｶｹﾞ)そうだ｡ お前らの誰か
１人でも ｵﾚに勝てれば➡
３人ｾｯﾄで 解放してやる｡
だが 負ければ…！
But if you lose...
...you'll become fish food in the bay of Edo!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)江戸前で 魚のｴｻだ！
えぇぇぇ～っ!?
とんだ茶番だぜ…｡
What a farce...
(勘兵衛)だが やるしかあるまい｡
Well, we have no choice, but to go along.
There's no other way to get out alive.
(勘兵衛)他に 生きて
ここを出る方法はないのだからな｡
Still...what's that woman thinking?
にしても いったい
なに考えてんだ？ あの女…｡
(勘兵衛)あれも
相当な博打好きだと聞いた｡
I hear she loves gambling too.
She plans to enjoy watching us squirm.
≪(勘兵衛)ｵﾚたちのｻﾏを見て
楽しむつもりなんだろう…｡
≪ｹｯ！ いけすかねえ女だぜ…｡
What a detestable woman.
さぁ 始めようか…｡
Okay, shall we begin? This game of life?
命の やりとりをな！
♪♪～
右ﾛｸか…｡ まずは ｱﾝﾀが親だ｡
Six to the right... well, you're the parent.
[Note: The term used is "oya" = parent; which means "dealer" in the game]
んだと ｺﾗ～！ 誰が 親だ！
What?! What parent?! I don't remember having a naughty kid like you!!
ｱﾝﾀみたいな悪い子
お母さん 産んだ覚えありません！
(ｱｶｹﾞ)いや… えっ？
Wha--? Huh?
This guy's eyes and his hand gestures... He's no ordinary guy.
《この男の目… そして 手つき…
やはり ただもんじゃねえな｡
Gin-san and I are the type who will never be loved by Lady Luck.
ｵﾚと銀さんは 幸運の女神からは➡
絶対に 愛されることのない存在｡
We have to let Mr. Luck Reader handle it.
やはり ここは ﾂｷﾖﾐのおっさんに
なんとか… えっ!?》
Huh? Not again. What's with these losing tiles?!
あぁ まただよ…｡ なに この配牌｡
どうすんの これ…｡
こんなん 何順あっても➡
What'll I do?! There's no way I can win with this!
上がれっこないよ…｡
That's why I didn't want to play. And I told you from the start.
《長谷川:あぁ～あ
もう いきなり➡
Man, he's already talking like it's hopeless.
夢も希望もないｺﾒﾝﾄ
しちゃってるよ この おっさん》
All right then. I guess it starts with me!
よ～し それじゃ まず ｵﾚからだ｡
ほらよ！
See?
Hey, you can't do that! You can't just throw away three tiles like that.
お～い!! 違えから！
いきなり３枚は ねえから!!
What? I can't? So what? I don't need them.
なに？ ﾀﾞﾒなの？ いいじゃねえか
いらねえんだからよ｡
It's over. He doesn't know the rules. Help, someone! Please help us!
(長谷川)終わりだ…
この人 ﾙｰﾙ知らないよ！
誰か 助けてよ～！
助けてくださ～い!!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ｸｯｸｯｸｯ…｡ こりゃあ 傑作だ｡
What a boner! The ones challenging me are total amateurs!
このｵﾚに挑もうというﾔﾂが
ど素人とはな｡
Fine, I'll let you do as you please, for a while.
いいぜ 大抵のことは 許してやる｡
このまま続行だ｡
So let's just continue like this.
This is impossible, I tell you...
んなこと言われても ﾑﾘだって～！
Even if us three losers team up to beat you, we can't possibly win!
くすぶり３人が
束になって かかったって➡
ｱﾝﾀには かなわないって！
Hey, hey, what's the matter, Hasegawa-san?
どうしたってんだよ 長谷川さん｡
おいおい…
まだ 勝負は
始まったばかりじゃねえか！
The match has barely started.
Akage is being so kind. It's too early to throw in the towel.
(勘兵衛)せっかく ｱｶｹﾞの旦那が➡
ああ言ってくれてるんだ｡
さじ投げるにゃ 早えだろ｡
そういうこった｡
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙなんてのは➡
Absolutely. Gambling isn't over until it's over.
下駄を履くまで
わからねえもんだ｡
I'm gonna shoot to win, my way!
ｵﾚは ｵﾚのやり方で
勝利を目指す！
《な… なんだ…
この 根拠のない自信は…｡
Wh-What's with this baseless confidence?! But his eyes look unwavering.
だが 揺らぎのない この目…｡
もしかしたら 何かが起こる！》
Maybe something's gonna happen...
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾛﾝ！ 小三元ﾎﾝｲﾂ ﾊﾈ満だ｡
Mahjong!
SHOUSANGEN HONITSU HANEMAN.
I knew it was hopeless!! It's no good.
やっぱり ﾀﾞﾒだ～!! 絶対 ﾑﾘ！
何も起こるわけない!!
We didn't have a chance!
一瞬でも 期待したｵﾚが
ﾊﾞｶだった～!!
I was a fool to even think it for a second!
Now, now, don't get too dismayed.
まぁ そんなに うろたえなさんな｡
This is just one game we lost.
たかが １回
振り込んだだけじゃねえか｡
《長谷川:そうだ…
ｵﾚたちには まだ➡
That's right. We still have Mr. Luck Reader.
ﾂｷﾖﾐの おっさんがいる！
あらゆる逆境をはねのける➡
The man with amazing luck who can turn the tide!
強運の持ち主！》
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾛﾝ！
えっ!?
Mahjong!!
Huh?
順ﾁｬﾝ三色… 親満だ｡
JUNCHANSANSHOKU OYAMAN.
絶対 勝てねえよ これ…｡
ﾀﾞﾒじゃん！ ﾀﾞﾒだってば！
Aww, come on! We can't! We can't win!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾎﾟﾝだ！ ﾁｰだ！ ﾛﾝだ！
Pong!
[Note: The following are all mahjong terms which lead to winning the game.]
Chow!
Mahjong!
Kong!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ｶﾝだ！ 当たりだ！
Akari!
Reach!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)そ～ら ﾘｰﾁだ！ ﾂﾓだ！
Draw!!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾀﾝﾋﾟﾝ三色ﾄﾞﾗﾄﾞﾗ！ ﾊﾈﾏﾝだ!!
KANPIN SANSHOKU DORADORA HANEMAN!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ｸｯｸｯｸｯｸｯ… 終わったな｡
It's over. Each of you has zero points. Meaning you have nothing.
ｱﾝﾀら 全員 ﾊｺ点…
つまり 持ち点 ｾﾞﾛだ｡
There's nothing you can bet with anymore.
もう 賭けるもんがねえ…｡
ｹｯ！
ﾀｺ天だか ｲｶ天だか知らねえが➡
Zero or nothing. So what?! A man doesn't win with points!
点数なんぞで
男の勝負が つけられるか！
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ほぅ…
じゃあ どうするんだ？
Hmm... Then what will you do?
もう… 次は 負けないんだから！
Well, I'm not going to lose the next one.
えぇぇ～っ!? 脱衣ﾏｰｼﾞｬﾝ!?
Huh?! Strip mahjong?!
昔 哲ちゃんや健ちゃんも
言ってた 映画で…｡
Tet-chan and Ken-chan used to say in the old movies...
[Note: This refers to the yakuza movies of Tetsuya Watari and Ken Takakura]
負けたﾔﾂは 裸になる…｡
(長谷川)誰だよ それ!?
"When you lose, you lose your shirt."
Who are they?
ｸｯｸｯｸｯｸｯ… おもしれえ｡
Sounds like fun. Fine. Let's continue.
いいだろう 続けようぜ｡
もう 半荘だ｡
(長谷川)えぇぇ～っ!?
I'm already close to winning it all.
Huh?!
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾗｰに必要な要素は
一に度胸…｡
The most important thing for a gambler is guts.
それは
満たしておるようじゃのぅ｡
He seems to be overflowing with that.
(華陀)しかし それだけで
切り抜けられるほど➡
However, gambling is not so easy that you can win with just guts.
この博打 甘いものではないぞえ｡
(勘兵衛)落ち着け ﾃﾒｴら｡
C-Calm down, you guys. One must not lose his cool, ever, in gambling.
(勘兵衛)博打において
冷静さを失うことは 絶対のﾀﾌﾞｰだ｡
たとえ 周りが炎に包まれようと➡
Even if you are surrounded in flames, you must keep calm and concentrate.
思考だけは
冷たく凍てつかせておけ！
(長谷川)凍てついてるよ！
もう 心も体も➡
I'm so cool my entire body is frozen!!
ｶﾁｺﾁに凍てついてるよ！
It's cold...
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾌﾌﾌｯ…｡
さてと
もう脱ぐものもないようだが…｡
Well now, it seems you have nothing else to strip.
(華陀)勝負あったか…｡
It's almost over. How boring.
つまらぬのぅ…｡
もう少し楽しめると思うたが…｡
I thought I could enjoy this a bit longer.
ﾂｷﾖﾐとまでうたわれた男が
この程度のものだったとはのぅ｡
To think, this is all the Luck Reader had.
お遊戯の時間は 終わりだ｡
Playtime is over. Next, it's your life. Sorry, but I'm gonna settle this.
次は 本当に命をもらう｡
悪いが
とどめ刺させてもらうぜ！
《長谷川:やはり
ﾔﾂは 伝説の雀鬼｡
He's the legendary Janki, after all. He's in a different class from us. This is it...
ｵﾚたちとは格が違う…
もう ここまでか》
Say mister, I wanted to ask you one thing.
なぁ とっつぁん… ｱﾝﾀに１つ
聞きたかったんだけどよ｡
ｱﾝﾀ ﾎﾝﾄに
その右目が見えた頃は➡
When your right eye was still good, were you really able to see luck?
ﾂｷってﾔﾂが見えたのかい？
ﾌﾝ どうせ
ｲｶｻﾏだったんだろうがな｡
He probably cheated. But relax. I'll be the legend from today on.
でも 安心しな… ｱﾝﾀの伝説は
今日から ｵﾚが引き継いでやる｡
うるせえぞ！ ﾃﾒｴは黙ってろや!!
Shut up! You be quiet!
なっ…｡
ﾌﾝ｡
Hah! If I could see luck, I wouldn't be one-eyed today.
ﾂｷが見えれば 片目などには
なっちゃいねえさ…｡
Kanbe, your man did a terrible thing. How will you settle this?!
((極道:勘兵衛！ ﾃﾒｴのﾂﾚがよぉ➡
とんでもねえことして
くれたんだよ｡
どう 落とし前つけてくれる!?))
ただ一つ 言えることはよ…｡
There's one thing I can say...
((極道:そういや 勘兵衛｡
By the way, Kanbe. I hear you have a very interesting right eye.
ﾃﾒｴ 大層おもしれえ右目を
持ってるらしいじゃねえか｡
なんでもﾂｷを読めるとか…))
That you can read luck.
(勘兵衛)はぁ…｡
ｵﾚは いつだって
後悔しないような選択肢を➡
I've always made choices I didn't regret.
選んできたってことだけだよ｡
((潰せよ！ ﾂﾚの命 助けてえなら
その右目を潰せ!!))
Smash it. If you want him to live, gouge out that right eye!
いつだって 自分がしたいように
やってきただけだよ｡
I've always done as I pleased. In gambling and in life.
賭けでも人生でも…｡
ﾌｯ…｡
Humph, and this is the result?
ﾌﾝ その結果が これだ！
In essence, a cheater, that's all you were. And I'll prove it right now!
しょせん ｱﾝﾀは
ここまでの器だったんだよ！
このｵﾚが 今
それを証明してやる！
《ｸｸｸｯ… もらった！
You're mine! Now I'll stop their breathing.
これで
ﾔﾂらの息の根を止めてやる！
ﾘｰﾁだ！》
ﾛﾝ!!
Reach!
Mahjong!!
なっ！
当たりだ！
Atari.
[Note: chiitoitsu = seven pairs]
CHIITOITSU. Damn right! He's got it!
(長谷川)ﾁｰﾄｲﾂ…
ﾎﾝﾄだ 当たってる！
な… 何だと？
Wh-What?! How?! I thought you didn't even know the rules!
なぜだ!? お前は ﾙｰﾙも
知らないんじゃなかったのか？
あぁ 知らねえよ｡
だから ｵﾚの好きなように打った｡
No, I don't. That's why I moved as I pleased.
本当に上がってたのも 今 知った｡
I just realized that I had completed my tiles.
なんせ ｵﾚは ﾃﾒｴが気に入らねえ｡
Besides, I don't like you.
ﾃﾒｴにさえ上がられなけりゃ
あとは どうでもいい！
As long as you don't beat me, I don't give a damn about the rest.
そんな ﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒな…｡
あっ！
Th-That's so ridiculous...
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…！
He really is ridiculous. But just now, the current of Luck changed.
ﾎﾝﾄにﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒだな…｡
だが 確かに今
ﾂｷの流れが変わったぞ｡
いくぜ！ とっつぁん!!
Let's go, mister.
(２人)反撃開始だ！
The counter move begins!
ﾒﾝﾀﾝﾋﾟﾝ ﾄﾞﾗﾄﾞﾗ ﾄﾞﾗｺﾞﾝ昇龍拳！
MENTANPIN Dragon Dragon Punch!
[Note: Dragon Punch refers to a term in the Drxxon Ball anime]
ﾄﾝﾅﾝｼｬｰﾍﾟｰ ﾘｰｼｬﾝ解放！
TONNANSHAPEI RINSHAN Release!!
[Note: "Release" refers to a term in the Naxxto anime]
ﾀｰﾊｲ！ ｼｮﾝﾊﾟｲ!! ﾁｮﾝﾎﾞ！
ﾌﾘﾃﾝ ﾉｰﾃﾝ ﾓｰﾊﾟｲ しっぱい!!
Taihai! Shanpai! Chonbo! Furiken! Noten! Mopai!
(２人)ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾄﾝ ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾅﾝ ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾘｷｯｸ！
Double East Double South Double Reach Kick!!
ｻﾞｺとは違うのだよ ｻﾞｺとは！
We're no small fries! We just ain't!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾊｧﾊｧ… ﾊｧﾊｧ…｡
これで 全員すっぽんぽん…｡
Now we're all naked. Let's settle it with the next game.
次のｹﾞｰﾑで決着といこうや！
ｸｯ…｡
《負けるわけにはいかない｡
I can't lose. She doesn't permit losing.
あの方は 負け犬を許さない｡
ここで負ければ ｵﾚは消される｡
If I lose now, I'll be killed.
どんなことをしても ｵﾚは勝つ！
I'll do whatever it takes to win.
どんなことをしてもな！》
Whatever it takes!
♪♪～
ｱﾝﾀらを 少し甘く見ていたようだ｡
I guess I underestimated you guys. But this is it.
だが ここまでだ！
I'll finish you off with this one deal.
この１局で
すべてをﾁｬﾗにしてやる！
ｱﾝﾀと勘兵衛 ２人まとめて
地獄へ送ってやろう！
I'll send both you and Kanbe to hell!
《もはや正攻法では
この流れは変えられまい｡
I can't change my strategy now.
だが ｵﾚには まだ奥の手がある…｡
But I still have a trick or two left.
悪いが
ｱﾝﾀらには消えてもらうぜ！》
Sorry, but you're gonna have to disappear!
うおぉぉ～っ！
必殺！ 猛虎幻魔牌!!
Lethal weapon! Giant Tiger Illusion Tiles!
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…！
《この間 わずか1000分の１秒｡
I can pull 1000 tiles per second! No way you can see my moves!
ｷｻﾏらには
ｵﾚの手を見ることもできまい！》
ふっ！
あっ…｡
Oh sorry... I was sitting for so long, my legs started to hurt.
あぁ 悪い…
長えこと座ってたから➡
足 痛くなっちゃって！
わざとじゃないから いや ﾎﾝﾄに｡
It wasn't on purpose. No really.
(ｱｶｹﾞ)ｸｯ…｡
あ～あ こりゃ大変だ！
Oh man, this is terrible. Let's put the tiles back. I'll help.
早く積み直さないと…｡
手伝いますよ！
や… やめろ！
えっ？
S-Stop!
いや 何でもない｡
No, it's nothing.
Damn! A few of the tiles ended up in the wrong position.
《まずい…｡
積み込んだ牌のいくつかが➡
予定外のところに入ってしまった｡
Especially that row they piled back up.
特に ｸﾞﾗｻﾝのﾔﾂが
積み直した あの山…｡
何としても
こちらに取り戻さねば…｡
I have to get it back!
大丈夫だ… 数手順 遅れはするが
問題ない！》
It's all right. I'll just delay a few of my moves.
いくぞ！
Here I come!
かかってこいや！
Bring it on!
(２人)うおりゃあぁぁ～っ!!
(３人の雄たけび)
(長谷川)あれ!?
Huh?!
あれれ？ これ 何つうんだっけ？
Huh? What's this called? Hey, I just...
いや 今 ｵﾚね 今回 親なんで
１つ捨てようと思ったんだけどね｡
I'm the dealer, so I was about to get rid of a tile and...look. It's all in place.
なんかね どうもね
上がってんだよね…｡
See... They're all paifu tiles.
(長谷川)ﾋﾟﾝﾌのみだけど…｡
ﾋﾟﾝﾌのみだろうが何だろうが
配牌時に上がってりゃあ…｡
That doesn't matter. If you've reached haipai...
天和…｡
Heaven's hand?
(華陀)天が 人に与えし幸運｡
Good fortune bestowed upon man by Heaven.
天和だと？ ﾊﾞｶな…｡
Huh?! Heaven's hand?! Impossible! How can that be?!
そんなﾊﾞｶなことが…｡
ﾊﾊｯ… 最後の最後で➡
So at the end of the end, Lady Luck had a one night stand with me!
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙの女神が 一夜の過ちを
犯してくれちゃったよ！
ﾊﾊｯ ﾊﾊﾊ…！
You did it, Hasegawa-san! I always knew you were someone who could do it!
やったな！ 長谷川さん｡
ｵﾚは ｱﾝﾀはやるﾔﾂだって
ずっと思ってたんだよ！
こんなことが… なぜだ？
How can this happen?! Where did I go wrong?
I feel like my life has changed. Maybe Lady Luck will love me forever.
ｵﾚは 何を どう間違った？
ﾌｯ… そんなもんさ 人生｡
Hah! That's life.
♪♪～
なぁ 銀さん…
女神が そっぽ向かないうちに➡
Say Gin-san, let's go celebrate before Lady Luck turns away from me.
ﾊﾟｰｯとやりにいこうぜ！
おぉ いいねぇ｡
Sounds good. How about we splurge on Dom Perignon with Dom Perignon?
ついに念願の
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘのﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ割りかい？
ほどほどにな！
Take it easy...
(ｱｶｹﾞ)うわぁ～！
この役立たずが…｡
You're hopeless.
♪♪～
ﾌﾌﾌ…｡
That's why gambling is...
これだから博打というやつは…｡
(長谷川)ぶぇっくしっ！
あれ？
[Thank you for your support this past year.]
[Please continue to watch.]
Anyway, you guys have to repeat the grade. So come to class another year!
Everyone, repeat one year.
Gin Tama begins another year!
But before that, there's something to do!
[After overcoming a reorganization, there's a new ordeal?]
[What happens to Gin Tama has not been determined yet. This is not a final decision.]